<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Sutkus Audio</title>
    <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Sutkus Audio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 22:26:17 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sutkusaudio.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Neanderthal tools is out!</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-09-06-game-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 22:26:17 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-09-06-game-release/</guid>
      <description>Hey there! Quick post about the game &amp;ldquo;Neanderthal Tools&amp;rdquo; for which I helped my friend Edvinas with the sounds on his game. Well it has been made public and available to everyone! Was chatting with him a few days ago when he mentioned that he will soon be having a meeting with the museum he has been cooperating. They have already deployed the game at the museum so I assume the majority of talk will be on what went right and wrong, where they could expand etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking into procrastination in another way</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-09-03-procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-09-03-procrastination/</guid>
      <description>What is procrastination to begin with? Procrastination is the action of unnecessarily and voluntarily delaying or postponing something despite knowing that there will be negative consequences for doing so (wiki quote). So in other words, we tend to slack off from doing what we know we need to do, knowingly that not doing this will get us in trouble but we still do it. But why is that? Why do we consciously choose to have this lifestyle and sabotage our emotional well being?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recording audio for a VR application concerning Neanderthal legacy</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-05-10-neanderthal-tool-sfx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-05-10-neanderthal-tool-sfx/</guid>
      <description>To get the best results one must be prepared in advanced to be able to get the most out of what he wants to accomplish. So here I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing the process I had with my friend Edvinas who is doing his masters thesis on interactive media in museums. A bit about the thesis is that they are researching on new ways to help museums convey history in modern day and that is by using VR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with FMOD in Unity</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-01-13-getting-started-with-fmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-01-13-getting-started-with-fmod/</guid>
      <description>Working in FMOD is quite a time saver with it&amp;rsquo;s capabilities in playing sounds at a given moment, adding effects based on the event that was sent from a game engine and easily shifting from placeholders to the final product. Middleware&amp;rsquo;s like FMOD are used by a lot of audio designers because it is a powerful tool in ones arsenal. And although scripting, coding and programming can sound daunting, with the little help of it and audio designer can do wonders in game development.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
