<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sutkus Audio</title>
    <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sutkus Audio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 15:20:50 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sutkusaudio.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project setup for better workflow on Unveiling</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2024-01-09-unveiling-project-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 15:20:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2024-01-09-unveiling-project-setup/</guid>
      <description>Before diving into a project, I believe that a crucial step is to plan the workflow that will guide the entire process. It&amp;rsquo;s essential to develop a structured approach and stick to it. To streamline my work, I&amp;rsquo;ve considered optimizing my use of Reaper and FMOD.
When working with Reaper, I find that naming conventions are crucial for understanding and efficiently handling files after rendering. As for FMOD events, I use a similar naming system to the asset files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exergale: audio in game</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2023-10-02-exergale-audio-pt1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 13:20:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2023-10-02-exergale-audio-pt1/</guid>
      <description>This year, I&amp;rsquo;ve been neck-deep in two projects, putting in loads of work, and truth be told, it&amp;rsquo;s been so hectic that I&amp;rsquo;ve neglected this blog for quite a while. But hey, better late than never, right?
Let me tell you about one of those projects, ExerGale, a VR game that&amp;rsquo;s all about flying, gliding, and climbing through a fantastic world. Right now, the game offers two modes: one where you can just soar around like a bird, and another where you hit a button and go on a crystal-collecting spree to rack up a high score.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rooted Warden - Global Game Jam 2023</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2023-03-02-ggj23-rooted-warden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2023-03-02-ggj23-rooted-warden/</guid>
      <description>The Global Game Jam 2023 took place on February 3-5. As you all know, this event brings together developers, designers, artists, and creative thinkers from around the world to collaborate, share ideas, and build new and innovative games in just one weekend. I attended it in Kaunas, Lithuania which is organized by LŽKA and the website of the event can be found here. This years art was done by an amazing artist - Teresė Žvinakevičiūtė.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using UE4 Hit Events in Blueprints</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2022-09-04-ue4-bp-hit-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2022-09-04-ue4-bp-hit-events/</guid>
      <description>Playing sounds on collision events is probably one of the most used event types in game audio. This can be by dropping an item on the ground, wall, table or bashing the item into other objects for example hitting a sword into a rock.
Preparing the Component In the components tab we add a procedural mesh component by pressing on the Add Component button, scrolling to the rendering section and finding the Procedural Mesh component (or upon pressing just typing the name).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random pitch changing for samples in Unity</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2022-01-12-random-pitching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2022-01-12-random-pitching/</guid>
      <description>Doing sound design you find yourself that you have a good sample to add to the game, but the sample is so good that any other would not fit, but you need more variations so that it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t fatigue the ears but just making a wee bit of pitch shifting and exporting it seems cheesy. Well now, what if we would do that in the game engine itself? Now that would be more stylish, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating wind from a noise sample in a game engine</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-10-15-generating-wind-sounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-10-15-generating-wind-sounds/</guid>
      <description>In here I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing about how I added an interesting system of wind SFX in Unity by using white noise and Unity&amp;rsquo;s sound mixer effects. I&amp;rsquo;d call this a dynamic wind SFX even. Because right know this is directly linked with the boat&amp;rsquo;s speed velocity. As it goes faster the wind becomes more high pitched and when it is going slower the wind is more on the low-end.
Generated Wind Effect I found this technique in one of Blipsounds video&amp;rsquo;s by Ryan Stunkel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neanderthal Tools Sample Pack</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-09-16-vr-neanderthal-tools-sample-pack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-09-16-vr-neanderthal-tools-sample-pack/</guid>
      <description>Hey there! As the game is open-source all the sfx used in the game are free-to-use. It might be hard a bit to download all the samples from the git directory for some as git and unity file system might not be that easy to use to everyone so I&amp;rsquo;ve compiled all the sounds into a sound pack to download. Also with it, made metadata into the sounds for easier tag searching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neanderthal tools is out!</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-09-06-game-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 22:26:17 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-09-06-game-release/</guid>
      <description>Hey there! Quick post about the game &amp;ldquo;Neanderthal Tools&amp;rdquo; for which I helped my friend Edvinas with the sounds on his game. Well it has been made public and available to everyone! Was chatting with him a few days ago when he mentioned that he will soon be having a meeting with the museum he has been cooperating. They have already deployed the game at the museum so I assume the majority of talk will be on what went right and wrong, where they could expand etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking into procrastination in another way</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-09-03-procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-09-03-procrastination/</guid>
      <description>What is procrastination to begin with? Procrastination is the action of unnecessarily and voluntarily delaying or postponing something despite knowing that there will be negative consequences for doing so (wiki quote). So in other words, we tend to slack off from doing what we know we need to do, knowingly that not doing this will get us in trouble but we still do it. But why is that? Why do we consciously choose to have this lifestyle and sabotage our emotional well being?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recording audio for a VR application concerning Neanderthal legacy</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-05-10-neanderthal-tool-sfx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-05-10-neanderthal-tool-sfx/</guid>
      <description>To get the best results one must be prepared in advanced to be able to get the most out of what he wants to accomplish. So here I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing the process I had with my friend Edvinas who is doing his masters thesis on interactive media in museums. A bit about the thesis is that they are researching on new ways to help museums convey history in modern day and that is by using VR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with FMOD in Unity</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-01-13-getting-started-with-fmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-01-13-getting-started-with-fmod/</guid>
      <description>Working in FMOD is quite a time saver with it&amp;rsquo;s capabilities in playing sounds at a given moment, adding effects based on the event that was sent from a game engine and easily shifting from placeholders to the final product. Middleware&amp;rsquo;s like FMOD are used by a lot of audio designers because it is a powerful tool in ones arsenal. And although scripting, coding and programming can sound daunting, with the little help of it and audio designer can do wonders in game development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/page/about/</guid>
      <description>The creative side Hey there! I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely enamored with the world of sound – those moments when a wind chime&amp;rsquo;s melody carries you away or when you can feel the power of deep bass in your bones. It&amp;rsquo;s like each sound has its own story to tell, and I&amp;rsquo;m all ears for it. There&amp;rsquo;s something about the mix of highs and lows, not to mention those futuristic synthesizer sounds straight out of a sci-fi flick.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
