<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fmod on Sutkus Audio</title>
    <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/tags/fmod/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fmod on Sutkus Audio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 13:20:50 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sutkusaudio.com/tags/fmod/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exergale: audio in game</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2023-10-02-exergale-audio-pt1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 13:20:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2023-10-02-exergale-audio-pt1/</guid>
      <description>This year, I&amp;rsquo;ve been neck-deep in two projects, putting in loads of work, and truth be told, it&amp;rsquo;s been so hectic that I&amp;rsquo;ve neglected this blog for quite a while. But hey, better late than never, right?
Let me tell you about one of those projects, ExerGale, a VR game that&amp;rsquo;s all about flying, gliding, and climbing through a fantastic world. Right now, the game offers two modes: one where you can just soar around like a bird, and another where you hit a button and go on a crystal-collecting spree to rack up a high score.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rooted Warden - Global Game Jam 2023</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2023-03-02-ggj23-rooted-warden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2023-03-02-ggj23-rooted-warden/</guid>
      <description>The Global Game Jam 2023 took place on February 3-5. As you all know, this event brings together developers, designers, artists, and creative thinkers from around the world to collaborate, share ideas, and build new and innovative games in just one weekend. I attended it in Kaunas, Lithuania which is organized by LŽKA and the website of the event can be found here. This years art was done by an amazing artist - Teresė Žvinakevičiūtė.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with FMOD in Unity</title>
      <link>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-01-13-getting-started-with-fmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>rokas@sutkusaudio.com (Rokas Sutkus)</author>
      <guid>https://sutkusaudio.com/post/2021-01-13-getting-started-with-fmod/</guid>
      <description>Working in FMOD is quite a time saver with it&amp;rsquo;s capabilities in playing sounds at a given moment, adding effects based on the event that was sent from a game engine and easily shifting from placeholders to the final product. Middleware&amp;rsquo;s like FMOD are used by a lot of audio designers because it is a powerful tool in ones arsenal. And although scripting, coding and programming can sound daunting, with the little help of it and audio designer can do wonders in game development.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
